Anthony Calderaio

Contact

Address

Palm Beach Gardens, FL 33418

Phone

2674102791

E-mail

anthonycalderaio@gmail.com

Certificates

Angular Certified Developer

Backend Development and API's

Node, MongoDB, Express, Mongoose

Machine Learning A-Z

@SuperDataScience

Python, R, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Algorithms

Personal Projects

Machine Learning API

A tool that serves built ML Models for public use (Almost Live)

Front End: Angular; API: Python(Flask); Hosting: EC2; Models include: Regression, Random Forests, Neural Networks...

> Video-Notes Video

Video annotation tool (V1.0.0 Live)

Written in Angular and binary available for download on

Mac
To Purchase: Link
Live hosted free version:
https://anthonycalderaio.
github.io/video- notes/home

Self-motivated and passionate Software Engineer with advanced and demonstrated experience spanning multiple industries like sporting, construction, data, and more. Technical skills like leveraging APIS, architecting UI's, and deploying ML models just to name a few. While the strongest skill lies with the Angular framework and UI web development, there is continuous need for new skills that is garnished through experience managing multiple projects simultaneously.

Work History

Senior Software Engineer & Data Scientist

2023-12 Current Agnes Intelligence, Palm Beach Gardens, FL
Leading the UI development to interface with backend
services, hosting, and presenting data for the Agnes
Intelligence Data Science company. UI is Angular. Also involved
in Data Science efforts. Internal disclosure is limited.

Software Engineer

2023-04 Current Dick's Sporting Goods, Inc, Pittsburgh, PA (Remote)

Converted contractor to full-time developer who maintained, and deployed UI for Cart/Checkout and My Account in Angular up to version 16. Utilized Kibana and Quantum Metric for performance evaluation and A/B testing, analyzing custom logs to pinpoint areas for improvement. Wrote test cases for bug fixes and features to ensure compliance with contracts, facilitating clear identification of breaches with Jest. Involved in phase-out of Bootstrap and Angular Material frameworks through custom code implementation. Demonstrated expertise in NgRx and observables to optimize application performance and functionality. Conducted GitHub Actions CI/CD jobs to enhance workflow efficiencies. Led the integration of SonarQube into the development process, devising a plan for its potential implementation.

Software Engineer

Papa John's, Atlanta, GA (Remote)

Migrated FTL and Gulp structure to Angular architecture, conforming and creating new APIs in Java Spring. Rewrote raw JavaScript and HTML into clean Angular code, collaborating with the backend team to refine REST API data structures. Created and adjusted CMS scaffolding for new and existing features. Led efforts to improve homepage performance by 20%, working closely with the scrum master to manage team resources.

Top Skills

Frontend

Angular, Rxjs, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, JQuery, Node, React, React Native,

Backend

APIS, Python, Flask, EC2, Express, Node, Java, Maven, MongoDB, postgreSQL

Data Science /ML

Python, R, Scikit Learn, Pandas, Numpy, Tensor Flow, Supervised & Unsupervised

Other Notable Skills

Terraform, XCode,
Github Actions,
Lambdas, Docker,
Google Analytics, A/B
Testing, Bootstrap,
Material Design, CI/CD

Software Engineer

2019-05 2021-10 Dycom Industries Inc, Palm Beach Gardens, FL (On-site to Remote) Spearheaded the development and maintenance of critical functionalities within Dycom Industries Inc's flagship Angular applications and internal Angular Library, optimizing data collection procedures for field operatives in the construction sector. Proficient in Material Design, RxJS, Angular Forms, HTTP functionalities, UX methodologies, and services, coupled with adept utilization of Python API with Flask. Collaborated closely with senior team members to orchestrate the conversion of an An-gular application into a Progressive Web App (PWA), facilitating offline accessibility and enhancing user experience. Possess hands-on experience with CI/CD pipelines utilizing Jenkins to automate the build and testing process, allowing developers to integrate code changes continuously.

Software Architect

VirtualFlow, Boston, MA (Remote)

2020-06 2020-08 Listed as a co-author on a publication doing pro bono sidework as architect of Angular 9 application. Worked closely with Harvard Ph.D and member of Angular team at Google to visualize and filter-sort thousands (and eventually millions) of Proteins and Ligands specifically to aid Covid-19 research. Publication can be found at this url:

https://chemrxiv.org/articles/preprint/A_Multi-Pronged_Approach_Targeting_SARS- CoV-2_Proteins_Using_Ultra-Large_Virtual_Screening/12682316/1

Software Engineer & SEO/SEM Specialist

2018-02 2019-05 Best Security Industries, Delray Beach, FL (On-site)
Ad Campaign management in tandem with Google
Analytics and Google Tag Manager. Wrote automated Apps
Scripts in Javascript with API's from the former.

Education

Bachelors of Science Computer Science

West Chester University Of Pennsylvania - Complete - Deans List

Masters of Science Computer Science

Georgia Institute of Technology, GA - In Progress (2/10 Classes)
Specialization in Machine Learning - 4.0 GPA